Finding Aid for Ann B. Davis papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann B. Davis papers 1944-2014 1956-2010
Davis, Ann B., 1926-2014.
15 GB online
1 oversize volumes
3.5 linear feet
2015044 Aa Ac
Ann B. Davis was a television and stage actress best known for her roles as Charmaine "Schultzy" Schultz on The Bob Cummings Show and as Alice Nelson on The Brady Bunch. Born in Schenectady, New York in 1926, Davis attended the University of Michigan and graduated with a degree in drama and speech. She went on to perform in television and stage productions from the 1950s until her death in 2014. The Ann B. Davis papers primarily document Davis' professional life, including photographs, correspondence, playbills, and promotional materials related to her work in television and theatre productions.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Ann Davis Norton Kemler (donor no. 11242 ), in March, 2015.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The Ann B. Davis papers are open for research.
Ann B. Davis (1926-2014) was born in Schenectady, New York on May 3, 1926. She moved with her family, including her older brother Evans and twin sister Harriet, to Erie, Pennsylvania at the age of three. Davis attended the University of Michigan, initially intending to become a doctor. She changed her major after seeing her brother perform in a production of the musical Oklahoma and graduated with a degree in drama and speech in 1948.
Davis moved to California in the early 1950s and was discovered while performing in cabaret musicals. She was cast in her first major television role as Charmaine "Schultzy" Schultz in The Bob Cummings Show (1955-1959). Davis won two Emmy Awards for Best Supporting Actress in a Comedy Series for the role in 1958 and 1959 and received a star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame in 1960. Following her portrayal as Schultzy, she appeared in a season of The John Forsythe Show and in commercials for Ford Motor Company.
Ann Davis' second major television role was as Alice Nelson on The Brady Bunch (1969-1974). She continued to be involved in Brady Bunch productions for the following several decades, including appearances in The Brady Bunch Reunion, The Brady Brides, The Bradys, The Brady Bunch Hour, and several Brady Bunch movies. Davis, working with Ron Newcomer, released a book containing Brady Bunch inspired recipes, Alice's Brady Bunch Cookbook, in 1994.
Davis continued to perform in plays and musicals throughout her television career, and following her role on The Brady Bunch her professional life focused heavily on stage productions. Davis performed in stage productions including Once Upon a Mattress in 1960 (she replaced Carol Burnett), Arsenic and Old Lace, Crazy for You, Follies, and The Nearlyweds, a play written for her by Brady Bunch producer Lloyd Schwartz. In addition to theatre and occasional film and television roles, Davis also continued to appear in commercial advertisements for companies including Shake 'n Bake and Swiffer.
Although Ann Davis continued to perform in television and theatre productions following her portrayal of Alice, the final 40 years of her life were mainly spent with an Episcopal community led by Bishop William C. Frey. She moved to Denver, Colorado to join the community in the mid-1970s, later relocating to Ambridge, Pennsylvania.
Ann Davis died at the age of 88 on June 1, 2014 after suffering a fall in the San Antonio, Texas residence in which she lived with Bishop Frey and his wife.
The collection is arranged into five series: Personal Files, Professional Files, Television, Theatre, and Visual Materials.
The Ann B. Davis papers primarily document Davis' career as a performer in television and theatre productions from the 1950s until 2014. The collection includes photographs, correspondence, and promotional materials documenting Ann Davis' involvement in television shows such as The Bob Cummings Show and The Brady Bunch, numerous theatrical productions, and other professional endeavors including work in advertising. Additionally, the collection includes some materials relating to Davis' personal life, including some biographical files, photographs, and personal correspondence. The collection is arranged into five series: Personal Files, Professional Files, Television, Theatre, and Visual Materials.
Subjects:
Bob Cummings show (Television program); Brady bunch (Television program); Davis, Ann B., 1926-2014.; Television actors and actresses--United States.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Actresses--United States.; Television production & direction--United States.; Theater productions--United States.
Contributors:
Schwartz, Lloyd.; Schwartz, Sherwood.
Genre Terms:
Digital file formats.; Photographs.; Television scripts.
- Personal Files, 1944-2014
  The Personal Files (1944-2014, 0.25 linear feet) series includes biographical materials, including materials for a potential biographical book, as well as materials documenting Ann Davis' involvement in her Episcopal community.
  - Biographical materials (Box 1)
  - Biography, 1985-1993 (Box 1)
    (Correspondence and drafts concerning potential book)
  - Clippings, 1980s (Box 1)
  - Letter about Porsche 914-G, September 14, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Memorials, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Paul Henning, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Religion, 1979-2009
    - "The Colorado Experience", 1979 (Box 1)
    - Newsletters, 1983-1985, 2009 (Box 1)
    - The Open Door, Volume 41 Number 8, May 1, 1985 (Box 1)
      (Saint John's Episcopal Cathedral, Denver, Colorado)
  - Things I Can't Bear to Part With, 1965-1974 (Box 1)
    (Correspondence and clippings)
  - Yearbook, 1944 (Box 1)
- Professional Files, 1960-2004
  The Professional Files (1960-2004, 0.5 linear feet) series includes materials related to Ann Davis' professional career that are not directly related to her roles in television and stage productions. The series consists of writings and correspondence from producer Lloyd Schwartz and advertisements, correspondence, and photographs related to Davis' work in advertisements for Swiffer.
  - Lloyd Schwartz, 1975-2009 (Box 1)
    - Blonde in Hollywood (Box 1)
    - If or When (Box 1)
    - Much A Dieux (A New Play in Two Acts) (Box 1)
    - The Nearlyweds, 1975 (Box 1)
      (Includes letter from Lloyd Schwartz)
    - RIPCO, 2009 (Box 1)
    - Trouble at Ford's (A novel of Intrigue, Deceit, the Television Business and the Assassination of Abraham Lincoln) (Box 1)
  - MCA Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Swiffer, 2003-2004
    - Advertisements, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Ann B. Davis Media Tour, April 7, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, circa 2003 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, November 2003, .ZIP file
      [BHL Reading Room Access Only]
    - "Resort" shoot, 2003 (Box 1)
  - USO, Vietnam, 1967 (Box 1)
    (Includes photographs)
- Television, 1950s-2009
  The Television (1950s-2009, 1 linear foot) series consists of photographs, promotional materials, and correspondence documenting Ann Davis' career in television, primarily her roles as Schultzy on The Bob Cummings Show and as Alice on The Brady Bunch.
  - The Bob Cummings Show, 1950s (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1950s (Box 1)
    - Emmy Awards, 1956-1959
      - 1956 (Box 1)
      - 1957 (Box 1)
      - 1958 (Box 1)
      - Publicity, 1958 (Box 1)
      - Memorabilia, 1958 (Box 1)
      - Photographs, circa 1958 (Box 1)
      - Congratulations, 1959 (Box 1)
      - Program, May 6, 1959 (Box 1)
      - Publicity, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Bob Cummings Show -- Schultzy's Dream World, 1955, [2015044-1]; original was 16mm film; b/w; sof; 00:29:25; MOV and .MP4 files; [Program 21 of the 1955 season of the Bob Cummings Show. Broadcast 5/22/1955]
  - The Brady Bunch, 1974-2009 (Box 1)
    - 1987-2002
    - Alice's Brady Bunch Cookbook, 1994, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Brady CD-ROM, 1995, 1 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 2)
    - "Brady, Brady, Brady" by Lloyd and Sherwood Schwartz, 2009 (Box 2)
      (Includes copy of book and letter from Sherwood Schwartz)
    - Brady Brides, 1981 (Box 2)
    - The Brady Bunch Hour, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Brady House, 1998 (Box 2)
      (Includes letter from Sherwood Schwartz)
    - E! True Hollywood Story, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Promotional Materials (Box 2)
    - Script -- "The Hair Brained Scheme," 1974 (Box 2)
  - Butterfly Island, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Mr. and Misses, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Myrnalene, 1961, 2 folders (Box 2)
- Theatre, 1948-2010
  The Theatre (1948-2010, 1 linear foot and 1 oversize volume) series is composed of photographs, playbills, correspondence, scripts, and promotional materials related to Ann Davis' roles in theatrical productions. The series also includes a scrapbook of Davis' early theatrical work, including materials from her time at the University of Michigan.
  - Arsenic and Old Lace, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Barn Theatre, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Cabaret Concert Company, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Cemetery Club, 1991
    - 1991 (Box 2)
      (Includes photographs and audio cassette)
    - Edmonton, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Mississauga, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Regina, 1991 (Box 2)
  - City Theatre Company Inc., Pittsburgh (Box 2)
  - Crazy for You, 1993-1996
    - 1993 (Box 2)
    - 1993-1996, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Erie Playhouse, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Follies in Concert, 2006-2007
    (At the Little Theatre on the Square)
    - 2006-2007, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Gala, Dress Rehearsal, and Performance Photos, June 1-3, 2007, .ZIP file
    - Performance video, 2007, .ZIP and .MP4 files
  - Holiday Memories, Playbill, 1992
  - Mornings at Seven, 1957
  - The Nearlyweds, 1975-1977
    - Granny's Dinner Playhouse, Dallas, Texas, 1975, 2 folders
    - Script, circa 1977
  - Once Upon a Mattress, 1964
    - Clippings, 1964
    - Correspondence, 1964
    - Photographs, 1964
  - Programs, Photographs, Clippings, 1957-1962
  - Rockers
    (Includes script and photographs)
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1952 (Volume 1)
    (Includes photographs and playbills from Ann Davis' time at the University of Michigan)
  - The Theatre Museum, December, 2010 (Box 3)
  - Three on a Honeymoon, October, 1974 (Box 3)
  - The Typist and the Tiger, 1963-1965 (Box 3)
- Visual Materials, 1956-1987
  The Visual Materials (1956-1987, 1 linear foot) series includes photographs and slides that document numerous aspects of Ann Davis' life, including promotional photographs related to her career in television and theatre and photographs from her travels to Italy, Thailand, and Vietnam.
  - Alice Smiles, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Ann Davis and Bob Cummings, Hour Magazine, January 1987 (Box 3)
  - Chemical Corps Display, Army Chemical Center, Maryland, January 4, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Denver Photos Taken at Family Conference by Barbara Benedict, June, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Drawings of Ann Davis (Box 3)
  - Friend's Pictures, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Italy, October-November, 1971, 6 folders (Box 3)
    (Includes photographs of the Forum, Palatine, Arch of Constantine, Servian Wall, Hadrian's Tomb, Baths of Caracalla, and other sites)
  - Laszlo Pic, Teddy Bear Affair, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - People Magazine, Proofs, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Photo Albums, 1960s-1970s, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Plaid Square Shirt Photo, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Portrait Photographs, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Thailand, September, 1967, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Vietnam, September, 1967, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Color Slides, circa 1971-1976, 10 slides boxes; 2 folders (Box 4)
    (Includes Brady Bunch, theatre, personal, and travel photos)